Guide to the Young Women's Hospital Aid records, 1912-1967.
Young Women's Hospital Aid records, 1912-1967.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Young Women's Hospital Aid records, 1912-1967.
2854
Young Women's Hospital Aid (Ithaca, N.Y.).
.4 cubic ft.
Reports, minutes, correspondence, newsletters, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, and other records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records of the Young Women's Hospital Aid, a social organization whose prime function was fund raising for the Tompkins County Hospital. Officers and members of this group were usually prominent women of the Ithaca, New York area.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Since its founding in 1913, the Young Women's Hospital Aid was a social organization whose prime function was fund raising for the Tompkins County Hospital. Officers and members of this group were usually prominent women of the Ithaca, New York area. The Aid assisted in the purchase of equipment for the hospital, and helped provide for the comfort and well-being of its patients. The organization also funded nursing scholarships with money raised through charity balls, fashion shows, and other social events. In 1964 the organization was dissolved and absorbed into the hospital's Department of Volunteer Services.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection includes reports of the Young Women's Hospital Aid Charity Ball, 1913-1963; minutes of the General Meeting, 1946-1963; correspondence, 1961-1964; mimeographed newsletters to members, 1961-1963; Special Committee minutes and reports, 1962-1963; and miscellaneous newspaper clippings, pamphlets, and other records.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Young Women's Hospital Aid (Ithaca, N.Y.).; Tompkins County Hospital.
Subjects:
Charitable societies.; Charities, Medical.; Women in medicine.; Women volunteers in social service.
Places:
Ithaca (N.Y.)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Link to a detailed list of the correspondence in Box 2.
- History, 1912-1967 (Box 1)
- Other Manuscripts - Charity Ball Reports, 1913, 1927-1933 (Box 1)
- Other Manuscripts - Charity Ball Reports, 1934-1940 (Box 1)
- Other Manuscripts - Charity Ball Reports, 1941-1949 (Box 1)
- Other Manuscripts - Charity Ball Reports, 1951-1959 (Box 1)
- Other Manuscripts - Charity Ball Reports, 1960-1963 (Box 1)
- Other Manuscripts - Misc., 1952-1964 (Box 1)
- Minutes of General Meeting, 1946-1953 (Box 2)
- Minutes of General Meeting, 1954-1963 (Box 2)
- Minutes of Board Meetings, 1957-1963 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, 1961-1964 (Box 2)
- Newsletters to Members, Mimeos, 1961-1963 (Box 2)
- Reports, 1960-1963 (Box 2)
- Reports and Minutes of "Special Committee", 1962-1963 (Box 2)
- Dissolution Signatures, 1963 (Box 2)